

8535 Highfield Rd, Park City, UT, 84098

🛮 +1(502)7759672 | 🗷 otis.true@gmail.com | 🎢 www.otismilliken.com | 🖸 https://github.com/Hokalaka2/ | 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/otis-milliken/

Summary_

Academic success in a school setting with a rigorous computer science course load. Fast learner, computer competency and good at mathematical reasoning. Experience with jobs that require learning new computer systems and technical details on the fly. Consistent work to develop my skills even outside of the classroom. Passion for problem solving and learning about computer science

Work Experience _____

Advanced IT Consultant

Middlebury, VT

MIDDLEBURY COLLEGE

Sep 2020-June 2021,June 2022-Aug 2022

- Worked in the Middlebury College Helpdesk dealing with the college's technical needs
- · Helped various technical problems including dealing with VPNs, network connectivity, printer issues, basic troubleshooting on a daily basis
- Experience learning new technical skills on the fly and under pressure. As well as customer service skills.

Park City Municipal and Mountain Trails Foundation

Park City, Utah

June. 2022 - PRESENT

TRAIL INTERN

June 2021 - September 2021

- For Park City Municipal, I helped in the Sustainability and Parks department with various projects including a new park fence, a trail counter system, and sign postage
- Experience talking with contractors, filling out grants, and administrative work
- With Mountain Trails foundation, I helped make new mountain bike trails. Gained experience using chainsaw, a variety of tools, and the basics for making mountain bike trails

CS 311 Tutor Middlebury, VT

MIDDLEBURY COLLEGE Jan 2022 - June 2022

- · Tutored for Intro to AI
- Gained greater understanding of the course material and on how to explain complicated ideas in simpler terms

Projects

CREATOR

Mountain Journal los dev

• Group, location specific, note journaling app for App Store

- Gaining experience with Swift, SwiftUI, Coredata, IOS dev
- https://github.com/Hokalaka2/MountainJournal

Relationship predictor Python

 CREATOR
 May. 2022 - June 2022

- Small project for class which feature a relationship predictor using Random Forest Technique with Decision trees
- Gaining experience with Decision tree optimization and other AI techniques
- https://github.com/Hokalaka2/AIFinalWebsite

Personal Website Ruby on Rails

• A personal website to showcase my ruby on rails learning

 CREATOR
 May. 2020 - Aug 2022

- Gaining experience with quick website developmen
- https://github.com/Hokalaka2/ResumeSite

Education

Middlebury College Middlebury, VT

B.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2020 - May. 2024

• 3.90/4.00 GPA

• Dean's List

RELEVANT CLASSWORK

• Systems Programming •Multivariable Calculus •Intro to Data Science •Geometric Modeling 422 •Artificial Intelligence 311 •Computer Architecture 202 •Math Foundations of Computing 200

OCTOBER 24, 2022 OTIS MILLIKEN · RESUME

Extracurricular Activity

Middlebury Club Soccer Middlebury College

March. 2022 -PRESIDENT

• Helped run a club of over 100 members. Including 10+ scheduling games, getting refs, finding field space, and managing large groups

• Competing in soccer at a decently high level

Middlebury Consulting Group

Middlebury College

MEMBER

- Sep. 2020 Aug. 2022 • Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.